

CONTACT

- **Q** 07 45 64 16 17
- ✓ rich.alan@proton.me
 https://alanrich.dev
- 56 Rue Riquet 31000, Toulouse France

COMPETENCIES

- Programming Languages
 - Javascript/Typescript
 - CSS
 - GraphQL
- Frameworks/Libraries
 - React
 - MUI
 - Redux
 - Next.js
- Testing & QA
 - Jest
 - Cypress E2E
- Development Tools
 - Nx
 - Git
 - NPM
 - Jenkins
- Architecture/System Design
 - Configuration-driven systems
 - Domain Object Modeling

LANGUAGES

- English (Maternal Language)
- Français (B1)

ALAN RICH

FRONT END DEVELOPER

PROFILE

As a front-end developer with five years of professional experience, I have worked extensively maintaining and debugging large-scale, configuration-driven systems. My recent role at Research Innovations Inc. involved resolving complex UI bugs within a framework powered by thousands of configuration files, demonstrating my ability to navigate highly abstracted systems. With an established record of remote work for U.S.-based companies in the national security sector, I bring adaptability, technical proficiency, and a self-driven attitude, capable of delivering results when the stakes are high and success is critical.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Innovations Inc.

2022 - 2024

Software Engineer II

- Used JS, TS, React & MUI to optimize front-end components, ensuring scalability and maintainability within a large Nx monorepo.
- Facilitated interaction between front-end components and underlying data models housed within domain-specific objects that encapsulated both data and business logic.
- Founded and lead a book club for Front End Devs to foster continuous growth and learning.
- Performed daily code reviews, always seeking opportunities to delete code.

OC Tanner

2021 - 2022

Software Engineer

- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to implement user-centric designs, ensuring a smooth and engaging experience for end users.
- Developed intuitive and responsive web interfaces using Javascript and React to optimize the user experience across various devices and screen sizes.
- Utilized GraphQL to efficiently fetch data from APIs, ensuring real-time, dynamic updates and improved performance.

Upwork

2019 - 2021

Freelance Web Developer

- Applied modern ES6+ features and React hooks to simplify state management, enhance reusability, and maintain clean, scalable codebases.
- Integrated RESTful API endpoints to dynamically render data, improving application efficiency and user engagement..

INTERESTS

- Pilates / Running
- Classical Philosophy
- Byzantine History
- Russian Literature
- French Comedy
- Wild Camping
- Minimalism
- Family Life
- Burning Man

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

•	Technical Writer	Upwork	2015 - 2019
•	Research Assistant	Illinois Institute of Technology	2013 - 2014
•	Organic Chemist	Nestle (Chicago)	2012 - 2013

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science

2004 - 2008

Benedictine University

Thesis: "A One-Pot Asymmetric Robinson Annulation in the Organic Chemistry Majors Laboratory", *Journal of Chemical Education*, 85 (2008)1531-1534, DOI: 10.1021/ed085p1531

Cours de Civilisation Française de la Sorbonne

2009 - 2010

Language and French civilisation studies through a program administered by La Fondation Robert de Sorbon and charged with enhancing the influence of French civilisation throughout the world.

Cours de Civilisation Française de la Sorbonne

2013 - 2014

I was briefly enrolled in a doctoral program but decided that academic research was not my calling. During my studies, I performed genomic analysis of human colorectal cancer cells affected by microsatellite mutations in the $Bax\Delta 2$ gene.

Alliance Française de Toulouse

2023

Cours Intensif de Langue Niveau B1